# Okpala Oluchukwu Chioma

https://www.linkedin.com/in/oluchukwu-chioma-okpala-456283139/

Independence Layout, Enugu. +234 816 211 3799

oluchukwuokpala1759@gmail.com github.com/chiomadans1759

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY AND OBJECTIVE

Talented software engineer with B.Eng degree and 3+ years in the implementation of data driven web applications. Experienced with all stages of the software development cycle, and adequate knowledge of technologies such as JavaScript, Groovy on Grails, CSS3/HTML5, PostgreSQL and MySQL. Also have experience with frameworks and tools such as Vue(vuex), React(redux), Node(express) Bootstrap, git and agile methodology. A fast learner that stays true to her fundamental values of Beauty, Integrity, Passion and Simplicity. Looking to join a team of very skilled and passion driven engineers that can inspire her to work and achieve beyond her current perceived limits, while contributing to a meaningful project and taking her career to the next level.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Okra Inc (okra.ng)
Lagos, Nigeria — Senior Frontend Engineer

Nov 2019 - PRESENT

Okra is ushering in the 5th generation of FinTech through real-time data.

# Chatdesk (<u>www.chatdesk.com</u>) Broadway, New York — Software Engineer

Nov 2019 - PRESENT

We have two main products at Chatdesk: **Teams** use sentiment analysis, tagging and other NLP techniques to automatically generate responses to our clients' customer feedback and comments from various CRMs (e.g. Zendesk and Front) and communication channels (e.g. Facebook and Twitter).

**Trends** uses our ML models to breaks down clients' customer feedback to tags and phrases, then performs sentiment analysis, named entity recognition and redaction to generate insights that are presented to our customers using various data visualization techniques. This gives a graphical visualization of customers' sentiments.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Built the core search functionality on teams using azure search indexing.
- Creating appealing and responsive UI and applying best user experiences
- Work on integrating *Teams* with our machine learning and response generation microservices.
- Enforcing programming best practices and standards to ensure that the code has adequate test coverage before deployment
- Work on *Trends* to implement data integration with third-party CRMs (Freshdesk, Zendesk, Ios App Reviews) and other communication channels e.g. Facebook

#### **SKILLS**

**Frontend Development** 

**REST API Development** 

Test-Driven Development

MockUp Design with AdobeXD

Version Control(git)

Project Management(Pivotal tracker, Gira, Trello)

#### **TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS**

### Languages

JavaScript, Groovy on Grails

#### **Styling tools**

Scss, css3, bootstrap, material UI

#### Frontend frameworks

React.js/Redux, Vue.js/Vuex

## Backend frameworks

Node.js/Express.js

## **Testing tools**

mocha, chai, chai-http, spork, sinon, sinon-http

#### **COURSES**

React - The complete react guide: Redux hooks, React router (Udemy)

The Coding Interview Bootcamp: Algorithms + Data Structures(Udemy)

Java In-Depth: Become a Complete Java Engineer(Udemy)

## Bloverse (bloverse.com)

## City Road, London — Frontend Engineer

November 2018 - November 2019

Bloverse is an AI driven content creation platform for modern journalism.

- I Built Bloverse v1 and v2 frontend with 2 other teammates with web technologies such as Vue/Vuex, node.js/Express, react/Redux, and bootstrap.
- I Built the bloverse admin app using vue/vuex, an interface for admins to easily visualize the statistical data of users reactions and satisfaction on the platform.
- I built the bloverse infographics page using D3.js and google charts.
- I monitored all stages of the software development life cycle in order to identify and resolve system malfunctions to meet quality standards.
- I also worked closely with the UI/UX team in using tools and methodologies to create representations for functions and user interface of desired product.

## Andela (andela.com), Lagos — Software Developer

August 2019 - September 2019

I lead a team of eight (8) other stackup developers in building a set of REST Api for a project while simulating real-world applications and solutions, wrote unit, integration and functional tests to test the API endpoints. I also worked as an Individual in building a complete project (Wayfarer), a bus trip booking app and also developed the frontend to consume the APIs and deployed it on heroku

## **Dev Center Square**, Lagos — Software Developer

August 2018 - November 2019

I worked as a full-stack freelance software developer focused on transforming a client's idea into finished products while constantly improving tools and infrastructure to maximize productivity and staying up to date with the ever changing technologies.

- I developed the frontend of a web application, "naija lotto", a now popular nigerian betting app using react/redux and bootstrap
- I developed the frontend of a job portal and added features like social signup with Google, Facebook, Twitter where companies signup and create job posts and signed up users apply to these jobs and track their applications.

## SunDimension, Abuja — Software Developer

March 2018 - October 2018

At SunDimention, I was responsible for developing functional and appealing web-based applications based on usability, providing website maintenance and enhancements, using a combination of markup languages to write web pages, creating cascading style sheets (CSS) that are consistent across all browsers and platforms and staying up-to-date on emerging technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Nigeria** — B.Eng in Electronic Engineering

September 2011 - July 2016

I graduated at the top 5% of my graduating class with a CGPA of 4.07 on a 5.0 scale during my undergraduate studies at the University of Nigeria Nsukka where I gained a strong operational research, problem solving and strong technical prowess which has been a stepping stone in my current career pursuit.

#### **REFERENCES**

Mr. Aneto Okonkwo (Professional Referee)

CEO and Co-founder, Chatdesk Inc 902 Broadway, New York, NY 10010 aneto@chatdesk.com +1 (650) 906-3961

## **Prof Charles Chidume (Academic Referee)**

President, African University of Science and Tech, Galadimawa, Abuja cchidume@aust.edu.ng +234 816 211 3799